Vidonian Club Records
Oskar Diethelm Library
Vidonian Club Records
1914/2019
The Vidonian Club records consist of several versions of its constitution, meeting minutes 1914- 2009, and correspondence. The collection has no series and needs to be reprocessed.
3.34 linear feet (8 boxes)
Vidonian Club
Oskar Diethelm Library DeWitt Wallace Institute of Psychiatry: History, Policy and the Arts Weill Cornell Medical College 525 East 68th Street, Box 140 New York, NY 10065
1977.0001
Gift of Shervert H. Frazier, MD, on behalf of the Vidonian Club, 1977 and 1978.
This collection is open for research.
The Vidonian Club was organized in 1914 by eight psychiatrists in New York City as a small social club to provide an opportunity for discussion of subjects of psychological and psychiatric interest, with reference to sociological and philosophical trends of the time. The Vidonian Club is an offshoot of the larger New York Psychiatric Society and continues to hold monthly meetings.
Vidonian Club; New York Psychiatrical Society; Psychiatry--History
The Vidonian Club records consist of several versions of its constitution, meeting minutes 1914- 2009, and correspondence. Much of the correspondence emanates from the Office of the Secretary (1916-1989), and deals with election of new members, attendance at meetings, the subject matter of monthly presentations, and the ordering of supplies. The correspondence includes obituaries and copies of some of the presentations given at monthly meetings. A few folders pertain to financial and miscellaneous affairs. The collection includes copies of the papers given by members at the club’s monthly meetings. The topics of the papers are often literary or historical, but oriented around psychiatry. Some deal more directly with psychiatric subjects. The collection has no series and needs to be reprocessed.
- No series
  - Constitution, 1920 - 1947; c. 1984 (Box 1)
  - Photocopies of historic records, Undated (Box 1)
  - Member lists, 1914 - 1989 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1940 - 1943 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1944 - 1952 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1951 - 1964 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1965 - 1970 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1971 - 1974 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1976 - 1979 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1980 - 1985 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1986 - 1995 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1997 - 2012 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1916 - 1928 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1929 - 1930 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1931 - 1932 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1933 - 1934 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1935 - 1937 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1938 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1939 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1941 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1942 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1943 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1944 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1945 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1946 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1956 - 1958 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1963 - 1977 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Treasurers’ Reports, 1951 - 1955; 1974 (Box 4)
  - Cash book, 1914 - 1951 (Box 4)
  - Finances and bookkeeping, c. 1961 - c. 1978 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1936 - 1959 (Box 5)
  - Papers given by members at Vidonian Club meetings, Undated (Box 5)
  - Papers given by members at Vidonian Club meetings, 1940 - 1949 (Box 5)
  - Papers given by members at Vidonian Club meetings, 1951 - 1954 (Box 5)
  - Papers given by members at Vidonian Club meetings, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Papers given by members at Vidonian Club meetings, 1956 (Box 5)
  - Papers given by members at Vidonian Club meetings, 1957 (Box 5)
  - Papers given by members at Vidonian Club meetings, 1958 - 1959 (Box 6)
  - Papers given by members at Vidonian Club meetings, 1962 - 1965 (Box 6)
  - Papers given by members at Vidonian Club meetings, 1966 - 1967 (Box 6)
  - Papers given by members at Vidonian Club meetings, 1968 - 1970 (Box 6)
  - Papers given by members at Vidonian Club meetings, 1973 (Box 6)
  - Papers given by members at Vidonian Club meetings, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Papers given by members at Vidonian Club meetings, 1974 - 1978 (Box 6)
  - Papers given by members at Vidonian Club meetings, 1979 - 1986 (Box 6)
  - Papers given by members at Vidonian Club meetings, 2000 - 2019 (Box 6)
  - Meeting List with dates, host, speaker and title of talk, 1914 - 2009 (Box 7)
  - List of speakers, 1977 - 1990 (Box 7)
  - Guest lists, c. 1990 - c. 1995 (Box 7)
  - Information on cups, Undated (Box 7)
  - Bios of members prepared for meetings – last name A-B, Undated (Box 7)
  - Bios of members prepared for meetings – last name C-K, Undated (Box 7)
  - Bios of members prepared for meetings – last name L-W, Undated (Box 7)
  - von Eifersucht Fund, Undated (Box 7)
  - Century Club menu, Undated (Box 7)
  - DVD, Richard Kogan, M.D. “Rachmaninoff, Dr. Dahl, and Posterity” Vidonian Club Meeting, Sept 16, 2013 and DVD, audio recording of Vidonian Club meeting March 24, 2014, 2013 - 2014 (Box 7)
  - Obituaries of members, 2017 - 2019 (Box 7)
  - Bound volume of minutes on shelf, 1914 - 1939 (Box 8)